# OHIA JANE CHIDERA

Software Developer, UX/UI Designer

### CONTACTS



Github https://
github.com/OhiaJanny

#### LINKEDIN

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ ohia-jane-chidera-458b39213

#### **EDUCATION**

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY BIOLOGICAL SCIENCE.

Second class upper division Federal university of technology Owerri (2016 -2021)

## TECH SKILLS

Visual Design

Web design

Interaction Design

React Js

HTML

Virtual DOM

Mobile App Design

Typescript

Redux Toolkit

Tailwind CSS

JQuery

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am software developer and UI/UX Designer with a trending view, high-quality and Pofessional approach with 3 years of practical experience building cuttingedge business solutions and web applications with a mobile-first approach. 3 years of practical experience in UX/UI Design.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Scrum Master. January 2022 - Till Date AB-Inbev, Lagos Nigeria

Assist the Product Owner With the Product Backlog.

Teach Scrum Practices and Principles.

Coach Team Members, Host Daily Stand-up Meetings. and ntroduce Agile Engineering Practices.

Keep all Parties on Track and Informed.

Implement Project Management/Best Practices.

To assist the Developers in building high-value products.

To coach self-organization and cross-functionality in the Developers

To remove impediments to the progress of the Developers

# UX/UI Design Lead

### Triisum.com, Pakistan January 2022 Till date.

Work closely with Design, Art and Programming Leadership.

Lead the UI/UX Department (composed by 2D/3D Artists, UI/UX Designers and UI/UX programmers) managing the UI/UX implementation of the ongoing projects.

Maintain ownership of the product vision and roadmap and improving the product development process.

Lead the team in expanding mastery of the business goals of each design request and pushing back on stakeholders with innovative UX/UI proposals.

Demonstrate high quality design practices. This includes participation in all aspects of UI/UX: research, ideation, strategy, interaction design, and visual design; Building a UX / UI style guide. Setting and maintaining UX / UI design standards.

# Full Stack Developer (C#, JavaScript, React Js, Bootstrap).

Price Waterhouse Coopers(PwC) Lagos Nigeria. August 2021 - September 2022.

Participating in the entire software development life cycle, debugging applications, and configuring existing systems.

Collaborated with team members to build Fullstack web applications with .Net, ReactJs and SQL  $\,$ 

Built reusable components and projects using React Js and Typescript

Writing clean, testable code using .NET programming languages (C#, MVC, Web API, .Net React, JS,)

professionally maintained all software and created updates regularly to address customer and company concerns.

Analyzed and tested programs and products before formal launch.

Troubleshoot coding problems quickly and efficiently to ensure a productive workplace

CSS

Bootstrap

C#

Agile Development

#### OTHER SKILLS

**JavaScript** 

**Commuication Skills** 

**Innovation Management** 

Copyediting

Interpersonal skills

Emotional Intelligence

Professional writing

Team collaboration

Listening skills

Documentation and reporting

#### **REFERES**

To be provided upon request.

# UI/UX Designer. Hadiel.com Lagos Nigeria August 2021- June 2022.

Worked on hadiel website. Took part from the research to final design. User Testing and User Experience research. Hadiel.com.ng designes availablle in figma for review.

UI/UX Designer.
Mercif.com Australia.
January 2021 - June 2022.

Worked on Mercif designs website. Took part from the research to final design. User Testing and User Experience research.

Mercif designes availablle in figma for review.

# Frontend Developer Spara Wallet Lagos Nigeria January - April. 2022

Developing new user-facing features using React.js
Building reusable components and front-end libraries for future use
Translating designs and wireframes into high quality code.
Optimizing components for maximum performance across a vast array of webcapable devices and browsers.

# Front-end Development Kartlog.netify Lagos Nigeria November 2021 - April. 2022

Developed and implementing highly responsive user interface components using React concepts.

Collaborated with senior developers to optimize components to work seamlessly across different browsers and devices Fetched data from APIs and tested endpoints using Postman

Development of dynamic and engaging web functionality and eCommerce using JavaScript and scripting languages

Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs Work closely with design team as technology advisor to help guide project scope.

# UX/UI Designer Kartlog.netify Lagos Nigeria November 2021 - April 2022

Designed logo, all graphics for online activity, and official website mockup

Conducted Usuability testing, heuristic evaluation

Worked with design team to create workflows and wireframes.

Also contributed components to the internal design system.

### Junior Frontend Developer.

March 2019 - January 2022

## Techlogix.com. Islamabad, Pakistan

Worked with multidisciplinary team of developers to build web based applications.

Used version control system to deploy projects Turned UI/UX designs into prototypes, creating excellent interactions from designs.

Collaborated with senior developers to optimize components to work seamlessly across different browsers and devices Fetched data from APIs and tested endpoints using Postman

# Web design and mobile app Designer SURETRIP.ng

Jan 2020 - May. 5 months 2022

Worked on user research interface paradigms and develop, maintain style guidelines to support mobile, web, ipad interface.

Ideate, produce, and present project deliverables such as user flows, wireframes, and concept designs to demostrate new feautures, dialogs, and other visual elements in the project.

Contibute to solving design challenges based on functional requirements of the media

Produce asthetically rich user interface designs in illustrator, figma Adobe XD for web and mobile aapplications.

#### **CERTIFICATION/COURSES**

Fullstack Developer, Price Waterhouse Coopers 2022

Modern React with Redux, Udemy 2022

UX/UI Design, Coursera 2021

Frontend Web Development with React, Coursera 2021

HTML, CSS and Javascript for Web Developers, Coursera 2021

Frontend UI Framework and Tools, Coursera 2021

The Complete Frontend Web Development Course, Udemy 2020